So, when you design a Kalman Filter,
在设计卡尔曼滤波器时
you need effectively two things.
需要定义两项
For the state, you need a state-transition function,
对于状态来说 需要状态转换函数
and that's usually a matrix.
通常是一个矩阵
So, we're now in the world of linear algebra.
下面介绍的都是线性代数知识
For the measurements, you need a measurement function.
对于测量值 需要测量函数
So, let me give you those for our example of the 1D motion of an object.
我画一个一维对象动作示例
We know that new location is the old location plus velocity to in this new this matrix.
我们知道新位置是旧位置加上速度 对于这个矩阵
You have a 1 over here, and a 1 over here.
这里是 1 这里是 1
The new velocity should just be
新速度就是旧速度
the old velocity because the 0 over here, and a 1 over here.
因为这里是 0 这里是 1
If you multiply this matrix with this vector,
如果将这个矩阵与这个向量相乘
this is exactly what you're getting.
就是这个结果
For the measurement, you only observe the first component of the place not the velocity,
对于测量项 只观察第一个位置组件 而不是速度
and that uses a vector or matrix like this.
使用这样的向量或矩阵
So, this matrix will be called F,
这个矩阵叫做 F 这个叫做 H
and this H. The actual update equations for Kalman Filter are involved.
卡尔曼滤波器的实际纠正方程有变化
I give them to you,
我会提供给大家
but please don't memorize them and I won't prove them for you,
但是请不要死记硬背 我也不会证明的
even the prove is very involved.
证明过程也很复杂
Every time I use images, look them up.
每次要使用时 我都会查询一下
There's a prediction step where I take my best estimate
对于预测步骤
x multiplied with the state transition matrix F,
我将最佳估计 x 乘以状态转换矩阵 F
and I add whatever motion I know, u.
并加上我所知道的动作 u
That gives me my new x. I also have a covariance that characters my uncertainty.
这样就得出新的 x 还有一个定义不确定性的协方差
That is updated as follows,
更新成这样
where T is the transpose.
T 是转置
There's also a measurement update step where we use the measurement z.
还有一个测量纠正步骤 我们使用测量值 z
We compare the measurement with our prediction where
我们将测量值与预测值比较
H is the measurement function that maps the state to measurements.
H 是测量函数 它将状态映射到测量值
We call this the error.
这个称之为误差
The error is mapped into a matrix S which is obtained by
误差对应的是矩阵 S
projecting the system uncertainty into
是通过使用测量函数预测
the measurement space using the measurement function protection,
将系统不确定性投射到测量空间获得的
plus a matrix R, the character is a measurement noise.
加上矩阵 R 表示测量噪点
This is then mapped into a variable called K which is often called the common gain,
然后映射到变量 K 通常称为卡尔曼增益
where we invert the matrix S. Then finally,
我们会倒转矩阵 S
we actually update our estimate and
最后 使用你很久都没见过的
our uncertainty using what ought to be
这个最神秘方程
the most cryptic equation that you've seen in a long time.
更新估算值和不确定性
Now, vote this down so that you have a complete definition,
我写出所有这些等式 使你了解完整的定义
but this is something you should not memorize.
但是你不需要记住
If you really wish to understand,
如果真要理解的话
this math happens to be
其实这些数学公式
just a generalization of the math I gave you to higher dimensional spaces.
就是我提到的高维空间数学公式的泛化
But I would recommend just not to worry about this.
建议不用担心这些公式
There's a set of linear algebraic equations
有很多在高维空间里
that implement the Kalman Filter in higher dimensions.
实现卡尔曼滤波器的线性代数方程